Guide to the Pennington Family Papers 1876-1975
George Fox University and Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends Archives
Pennington Family Papers
1876-1975
George Fox University and Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends Archives 416 North Meridian Street Newberg, Oregon 97132 archives@georgefox.edu http://www.georgefox.edu/offices/murdock/Archives/index.html
Pennington, Bertha May; Pennington, Levi Talbot, Dr.
MS.37
3.5 cubic feet three archival boxes and two records boxes.
All unnecessary binding has been removed, including staples and paper clips, as a means not to obstruct or ruin any of the other materials. There are still occasional rips though and some little scraps of paper, as well as some stains and marks caused by age and usage. While the staples and paper clips have been removed, some of the materials have rust on them. Yet, despite this, the collection is still im pretty good condition.
This collection mostly follows the later life of Levi Talbot Pennington. The materials that this collection includes are letters, poems, photographs, diaries, and personal notes. These materials ultimately provide insight into aspects of Pennington's life, such as his time as president of Pacific College and his Quaker religion. This collection is useful for those who want to want to learn more about the Quaker religion and the history and culture of Pacific College, which is now known as George Fox University.
Box Leg.44
This collection chronicles the majority of Levi Talbot Pennington's life, particularly his career as president at Pacific College (now known as George Fox University), the poetry he wrote, and his life as a Quaker. The collection has several sources that talk about Pennington's early life, and those were made near to and after his passing. The collection consists of letters, photographs, personal notes, poems, passports, diaries, sermons, newspaper articles, and general records. This collection is informative and useful for those who wish to learn more about the history of George Fox University and its culture, the values and teachings of the Quaker tradition, and the life of one of the presidents of George Fox University. With the knowledge available in this collection, people who view it will come to a deeper understanding of George Fox University and the Quaker tradition.
This collection is available for use.
Levi Talbot Pennington lived from 1876 to 1975, from 1911 to 1941, he served as president of Pacific College, which later came to be known as George Fox University. Throughout his life, he was a follower of the Quaker tradition, which can easily be seen in most of the collection, particularly in regards to his poems, letters and personal notes. During his life, he was married twice, and authored several books, including three collecting his poetry and one reflecting on his life. When he passed away, he had just turned 99 years old. After his passing, Pennington was survived by his children, including daughter Mary Beth Pennington, his grandchildren, and his great-grandchildren.
Pennington, Mary; Hoover, Herbert Clark, Pres. U. S.; Kidd, Rebecca; Minthorn, Henry John, Dr.
sermons
Quakers; Schools and Colleges; Pacific College (Newberg, Or.); Christmas cards--1940-1960.; Presidents--United States; Early twentieth century; Commencement Ceremonies; Temperance; Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends Church; American Friends Service Committee; Society of Friends; Peace--Study and teaching; Newberg, (Or.); Correspondence; Administration--Academic Affairs; Obituaries; Campuses; Buildings; Homecoming; Chapel; College athletics; Spiritual formation; Temperance; Alumnae and alumni
Diaries; Photographs; Student Life; Home and Family; Public Finance; Religion; Sound Recordings; Media and Communication; Transportation; Journalism; Scrapbooks; Economics and Banking; Fishing and Canning; Literature; Children and Youth; Publishers and Publishing; Colleges and Universities
Newspapers; Periodicals
- Correspondence, 1
  - Christmas Cards Sent, 1/1
  - 50th Wedding anniversary, 1/2
  - 90th Birthday Cards with messages 1965, 1/3
  - Some of the 92nd Birthday Greetings, 1/4
  - Christmas cards 1967, 1969, 1/5
  - Holiday Cards-1970, 1/6
  - Christmas Cards Received 1972, 2/1
  - Christmas Cards - received 1973 (Other cards included), 2/2
- Published Material, 2
  - LTP Poems, 3/1
  - LTP-Pacific College #1 of 2, 3/3
  - LTP-Pacific College #2 of 2, 3/4
  - Linfield College 66th Annual Commencement Program Flyer, 3/5
  - LTP Collection Poems-Clippings, 3/6
  - Misc., 3/7
  - LTP Publishing 1948 #1 of 5, 3/8
  - LTP Publishing 1948 #2 of 5, 3/9
  - LTP Publishing 1948 #3 of 5, 3/10
  - LTP Publishing 1948 #4 of 5, 3/11
  - LTP Publishing 1948 #5 of 5, 3/12
  - LTP-Newspaper Articles, 3/13
  - LTP-Herbert Hoover, 3/14
  - Letter about publishing-1968, 3/15
  - LTP-articles about his later life and passing, 3/16
  - LTP-Documents celebrating his accomplishments and work, and others that are in memory of him, 3/17
- Modern America Poetry Modern British Poetry book, Photographs and other Audio-Visual Material, 3
  - Modern American Poetry Modern British Poetry book, 4/1
  - Class mates in academy and College MP Mary Pennington Pearson class of 1920, 4/2
  - Silvertone Recording Wires, 4/3
  - Bertha May Pennington Pulcipher Bridal Book 1954, 4/4
  - Photo Album #1 Campus Life, 4/5
  - Photo Album #2 Pictures, 4/6
  - Photo Album #3 Pictures, 4/7
  - Photo Album #4 Pictures (Pasadena, Cal.), 4/8
  - Photographs, 4/9
  - Photograph Envelope, 4/10
- Personal Information and Notes, 4
  - Finances, 5/1
  - Modern American Poetry Modern British Poetry notes, 5/2
  - Travel Diaries, Calendars, Passports 1930-1931 Other Notes undated; #1 of 5, 5/3
  - Travel Diaries, Calendars, Passports 1930-1931 Other notes undated; #2 of 5, 5/4
  - Travel Diaries, Calendars, Passports 1930-1931 Other notes undated; #3 of 5, 5/5
  - Travel Diaries, Calendars, Passports 1930-1931 Other notes undated; #4 of 5, 5/6
  - Travel Diaries. Calendars, Passports 1930-1931 Other notes undated; #5 of 5, 5/7